# KAVINDA WEERAKOON

Toronto, ON, Canada | P: (289)-943-5686 | kavinda@kwnetic.com | kwnetic.com

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY - FRONTEND ENGINEER

An experienced, dedicated, and motivated frontend software developer with over a year of experience with a strong passion for learning and building frontend web applications. Has exceptional communication skills and has been coding for over 15 years as a hobby. Excels in collaborative and dynamic work environments and cultures.

#### **EDUCATION**

Frontend Simplified Bootcamp - (Website)

Harvard University - CS50x Introduction to Computer Science

November 2021 - May 2022

January 2022 - April 2022

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Proficient in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6+, React.js (+hooks), npm, Git, GitHub, Jest, Vue.js, Tailwind CSS, TypeScript, and SASS, familiar with Redux, yarn, SQL, Firebase, PHP, Java, C#, C++, and Python.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

KWnetic Remote

Freelance Frontend Engineer

November 2021 - Present

- Developed and maintained 15+ scalable, responsive, multi-platform and SEO-friendly landing page websites for clients using HTML5, CSS3 + BEM, JavaScript ES6+, React.js, TypeScript and SASS
- Implemented best practices to optimize multiple webpages' performances for a high volume of clients in a short period
- Dealt with reaching out to multiple clients for freelance work and made sure clients had an exceptional user experience during the whole process
- Gained exceptional project management skills working with multiple clients at once

Amelia - (Website)

Toronto, ON, Canada

Full Stack Software Engineer Intern

May 2022 - July 2022

- Developed maintainable and testable code in a mobile and web application used by over 10,000 users in Canada
- Shipped new product features using the React Native framework across iOS and Android applications tested with Jest
- Managed the lifecycle of the mobile and web application development using CI/CD deployment processes
- Collaborated with the Tech Lead, other interns, UI/UX designers, and the founders in a scrum agile environment
- Used Slack, Figma, Trello and GitHub to manage communication and workflows.

## **PROJECTS**

# Movie Database React App – "Flicks" (View project) – (GitHub)

May 2022

- Designed, developed, and hosted a movie lookup app made using HTML5, CSS3 + BEM, JavaScript and React.js
- Implemented and executed Axios to fetch data from OMDb API asynchronously and displayed data as media content
- Included SEO, responsive, multi-platform, and hosting support
- Able to handle 20 concurrent users at a time and handle up to 1000 daily requests

## Social Media Clone - Twitter (View project) - (GitHub)

April 2022

- Created a responsive social media web app clone using HTML5, CSS + BEM, JavaScript, React.js, and Firebase v9
- Stored and fetched tweets using Firebase Cloud database
- Utilized Twitter's API to fetch tweets and display them on the user interface with the best UI/UX principles

#### **ADDITIONAL**

**Languages:** Fluent in English, limited working proficiency in French **Interests:** Gaming, lifting weights, racing with fast cars on the track

#### REFERENCES

Available upon request